hello guys my name is the chana welcome
back to my C++ series so today we're
gonna be talking all about structured
bindings in C++ this is specific to C++
17 structured bindings are a new feature
that let us deal with multiple return
values a little bit better now I did
make a video about how to deal with
multiple return values in C++ check out
that video if you haven't already I'll
have it linked up there and this is kind
of extending upon that with kind of a
new way of how we can deal with this
specifically how we can deal with tuples
and pairs and returning things like that
because structured bindings just let us
kind of simplify our code make it a lot
cleaner than what it was in the past in
that video about how to deal with
multiple values in C++ I did
specifically mention that I like structs
and I like to return basically instances
of structs which contain the members of
data that I actually want that's how I
personally like dealing with multiple
return guys that could have potentially
changed with this introduction of
structured bindings and in fact it has
changed because over the past like year
or two really in my own code I've kind
of noticed that I've been using tuples
and like pairs and tires and I've been
using that kind of stuff basically
having multiple return value soaked into
like a tuple I've been using that a lot
more often because structured bindings
help me actually make my code still
manageable because I used to absolutely
hate what it was like before in fact
let's take a look at what it was like
before so I'm gonna write a very simple
example just running it from scratch
here to make it really really obvious
and what I'll do here is just write a
function that creates a person now a
person is a nice example because you
might want to store more details about a
person than just for example their name
in this case we'll deal with their name
and their age so we'll write a function
called create person we'll need to set a
return type which we will set to SCD
tuple and this is gonna contain the
actual kind of multiple return values
that we want to deal with in this case
we'll deal with a string for the name of
the person and then an integer for their
age and we'll include string up here as
well and of course we don't need to
actually write age just the type so we
have a string and int over here we'll
simply return in this case will be nice
and simple we'll just simply return
as the name and then an age watch for my
age which is the 24 so now we have
basically a mechanism to return two
different types of data a string and an
INT without having to like create a
struct or anything like that or just
like pass parameters by reference or
like as a pointer nice and simple and
clean of course in this case you could
just use a pair because there are two
variables that this actual data
structure is holding however with the
tuple you can of course expand this to
containers basically as many values as
you want so the in previous versions of
C++ you had a few options for how you
would deal with this well write some
code to kind of show that so I'll write
STD tuple string and and you can see
already the type is a little bit messy
but we'll have our person here then
we'll set that equal to create person
now to simplify this a little bit more
you can just use order here in fact
that's what I probably would do in this
case but now we have the task of
accessing the data and this is where it
gets really really annoying so basically
the way that you can't just do person
dot you know name as if it was a struct
you have to use STD get and then as a
template argument the index of the data
you want to get so zero for example
would return the name the first variable
which is a string and then if I used one
here that would return the age so
basically to get this and you put the
actual variable as a parameter here so
to get the actual string which is the
name I'd have to write code like this or
you can use auto of course and then the
age as well would look a little bit
cryptic and it would basically be the
same with sed get one and this is a
little bit well it's it's just not nice
I probably would never use a triple for
this case now there is something called
STD tie which is a little bit nicer than
this you still have to actually create
true variables so name and age over here
but what you can actually do is just
pass them in here they get passed in by
a reference name an age and then just
set this equal to create person and this
is a little bit nicer than all of this
of course we don't have our actual
person variable because we don't there
is no person right it's not like it's a
struct it's not like it's its own type
it is just a container a tuple in this
case that holds what we want which is a
string and an int so this does look a
bit nicer and I would probably be a
little bit more inclined to do it this
way how
whether it still takes up like three
lines of code it still does not look
nice and I still probably would use a
struct and just basically create a
person so that then I could return that
and then obviously just access it by
person name and person till age as I
showed in that C++ video about multiple
return types now this is the part that
you've been waiting for this is where
C++ 17 brings us a new feature called
structured bindings that solves all
these problems and makes our code look
really nice instead of doing all of this
I will raise my person up here instead
of doing all this we still keep this as
a tuple we don't need STD tie or
anything like that all we need to do we
can get rid of these two lines of code
all we need to do is use the word author
followed by the two names that we give
to our variable so we can give these any
names we want whatsoever so name and age
would be good in this case and then we
just set it equal to create person and
that is it this is a string this is an
int it does everything for us perfectly
and if we wanted to like we could print
this we could do anything we want with
these variables because now they're
totally just in this scope and totally
accessible to us now keep in mind this
feature is only in C++ 17 and newer
versions of say plus plus so if this
does not compile for you make sure
you're not compiling once a plus 14 or
11 or anything like that make sure you
switch your sales plus version to say
plus plus seventeen specifically in
Visual Studio we can go over here into
properties and then go into say C++
language and then make sure that our
language standard is actually set to
Sables plus 17 standard if it's set on
default it may not work so for example
if I do switch it to default and I try
and compile this code you can see that
it will not compile we will get an error
saying that name is uncontacted
identifier and in fact we will get an
error that tells us what we need to do
it says the language features structured
bindings requires compiler flag c++ 17
so to switch it to that just make sure
you go into your properties and set your
sample stuff language standard to be c++
17 now of course if you're using a
different IDE or a different build
system than Visual Studio like I am in
this case then you'll have to do the
equivalent for that but save us plus 17
is what you need to have structured
bindings to use structured bindings like
this I want to show you guys one more
example so what I've got here is some
code from the
OpenGL series specifically the shader
compilation' code I did talk about the
possibility of using tuples in that
video as well which I might link in the
top right corner but basically what we
ended up doing was we need to pass a
shader which we took in a file path
floor and then we just read that file
and the result of this function was
splitting up that shader file into two
different strings based on the shader
type and so what we did to support that
is we returned a struct as you can see
if we look at what that struct is we
have a vertex sauce and a fragment sauce
so what I'm going to do is change this
to use structured bindings so that we
don't need this struct at all so alt
delete the struct will come over here
into our path shader we're not going to
use a pair here we'll use a tuple the
reason is that this theoretically could
support more types than just fragment
and vertex shaders which is what we've
got there right now so what I'll do is
just use the triple again you could use
a pair then later change it into tuple
it shouldn't break any code but just
giving a reason behind why I'm using to
build parent table in this case
identical results okay so we'll come
over here and we'll also include that
tuple and now I will hop over into my a
bus bus code I will change this to be
the same thing the cool thing is that
this return statement does not change at
all because we still construct the tuple
in exactly the same way but if we come
over here into where we actually use
this code which is up here instead of
using this shader program source type
and then doing source type vertex or
source table fragments source instead of
that we can now just use order followed
by vertex source and fragment sauce and
then just set that equal to pass header
and then into the create a function this
also disappears and just simply becomes
a vertex sauce and fragments sauce now
in this case you can see that this does
not compile because we need to switch
this to be C++ 17 which it currently is
not so let's just do that here it is
language standard and we'll set that to
C++ 17 now you can see the error goes
away and this is what we're left with so
really simple really clean code if we go
back to our header file you can see we
got rid of that shader sauce struct
altogether we know how one less type
floating around which is a lot cleaner a
lot easier because this is really the
only case in our code where we actually
want to use that shader saw struct this
was used all around our code base
you wouldn't want to wear this into a
tuple and use structured bindings like
this but in this case it just makes so
much sense why have a type that you only
use once that I don't really like the
idea of that because it just clutters up
your code base you have an extra type
floating around not necessary you can
just use it structured bindings and
tuples or pairs in this case and I hope
you guys enjoyed this video and that you
kind of benefited from seeing a
real-world example if you did you can
drop a like below you can also help
support this channel by going to patron
home for slash that show huge thank you
as always to all the patrons that made
this video possible
drop a comment below on what you would
like to see covered in C++ next I do
have a very long list I think there's
like 20 items are sort of what I'm gonna
get through I'm gonna try and put out a
video for you as often as possible so
make sure that you subscribe if you
haven't already and I will see you next
time goodbye
[Music]